

# William (Marcus) King

Software Developer

## **Personal Info**

wmarcusking98@gmail.com

(587) 892-3077

Calgary, AB, Canada

## Education

B.Sc. in Computer Science
University of Victoria
2016 - 2021

## Skills

C# - Experienced

C++ - Experienced

Git - Expert

Java - Experienced

Python - Experienced

Typescript - Experienced

Unreal Engine - Beginner

Unity - Beginner

GraphQL - Experienced

PostgreSQL - Experienced

## Links

LinkedIn -

www.linkedin.com/in/marcus-king-

b71418158

<u>GitHub - https://github.com/king-</u> mork

# **Summary**

Motivated software developer with 2+ years of experience developing tools for VFX/animation pipelines. Experienced in C++, Python, Typescript, and Java. Combining my knowledge with my drive to learn to produce the best quality work I can.

# **Work Experience**

#### Software Developer, DNEG

November 2021 - July 2024

- Implemented and deployed a web UI that used SVG and D3.js to render a node-based visualization of assets and their relation to one another, including more detailed information on each asset.
- Established a template and dev workflows for the future creation of web-applications at DNEG.
- Contributed to the planning of projects and creation of design documents that would expand the usage and efficiency of GraphQL services and APIs.
- Traced and debugged support issues through applications with multiple layers of dependent interfaces.
- Updated and migrated tools owned by the Data Frameworks team to be compliant with our team's current dev workflows as well as more modern build environments.
- Converted dozens of DNEG's extensive catalog of Python libraries, DCC plugins, and scripts to be Python 3 compatible.
- Wrote both developer-facing and user-facing documentation on the intended usage of libraries and features.

## Java Technologies Analyst Co-op, CGI

May 2018 - December 2018

- Programmed numerous test cases in Java for a Selenium-based automated testing framework to catch regressions in a BC Government web-application.
- Monitored and investigated failures reported in the automated tests across the QA, Test, and Production environments.
- Created a document cataloging the suite of test cases and the scope of the application that each test case covered.

## кетегепсеs

Virginia Nearing, DNEG virginia.nearing@gmail.com

Ashley Whetter, DNEG ashley.whetter@dneg.com

Brandon Wiebe, DNEG brandon.wiebe123@gmail.com